A Guide to the Sheryl Tadlock Watson Papers, 1959-1965: SC 0275
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Sheryl Tadlock Watson Papers,
1959-1965
Special Collections, James Madison University
Watson, Sheryl Tadlock
SC 0275
.4 cubic feet; 1 box
The Sheryl Tadlock Watson Papers, 1959-1965, document Tadlock's time as a student at Madison College during the 1960s. Freshman orientation materials, correspondence, policies and regulations regarding conduct, coursework, program cards, event programs, and ephemera are represented in the collection.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Sheryl Tadlock Watson in September 2018.
Bio/Historical Note
Sheryl Bett Tadlock Watson of White Stone, Virginia matriculated at Madison College in the fall of 1961. While at Madison, Watson was a member of SGA, Sigma Phi Lambda, the Math Club, the Cotillion Dance Club, YWCA, and the Baptist Student Union. She graduated in 1965 with honors with a Bachelor of Science degree in mathematics and a minor in physics. It was Business 340: Data Processing for Business, a course she took during her last semester at Madison, that inspired Watson to pursue a career in programming/analysis.
Her sister, Virginia Lee Tadlock Brown, graduated with a degree in mathematics in 1962.
After graduation in 1965 through 1972, Watson worked for Bellcomm, Inc. Watson's work at Bellcomm assisted in the implementation of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration's (NASA) Apollo lunar missions. Specifically, Watson prepared lunar landscape scenes for astronaut training and did trajectory analysis of all phases from launch to reentry. After 14 years as a homemaker and stay-at-home mom, Watson joined Advanced Technology Systems (ATS) in 1987, eventually becoming a Cobol programmer, supporting Housing of Urban Development (HUD) Federal Housing Administration (FHA) loans. Watson retired in February 2014.
John and Sheryl Tadlock Watson endowed the Tadlock Watson Scholarship "in appreciation of the education Sheryl received during her undergraduate years at Madison College and of the many benefits derived from the emphasis placed upon education by [Sheryl's] parents." Tadlock-Watson Scholars are selected based on the student having a documented disability, with priority given to students with learning disabilities, and who in their first year as recipients, have a demonstrated need for financial assistance.
Scope and Content
The Sheryl Tadlock Watson Papers, 1959-1965, document Tadlock's time as a student at Madison College during the 1960s. Freshman orientation materials, correspondence, policies and regulations regarding conduct, coursework, program cards, event programs, and ephemera are represented in the collection.
Watson was an active member in student organizations and participated in various extracurricular activities. Materials related to these activities include Baptist Student Union newsletters and programs for the theatre productions Skin of Our Teeth, Summer and Smoke, The Limestones, Lady Madison Goes to the White House, "Ain't Dat So," and Under Milk Wood. Additional programs are related to May Day, Founders Day, convocations, Moving-Up Day, and a concert by The Lettermen. Correspondence, while largely arranged together, can be found in other files, specifically with the freshman orientation materials.
An itemized listing of the materials in this collection was created by the donor and is included in the collection control file.
Arrangement
The collection is primarily arranged topically into folders and further arranged chronologically.
Bibliography
"Tadlock Watson Scholarship." https://www.jmu.edu/scholarships/finaid/tadlock-watson-scholarship.shtml (accessed October 8, 2018).
Bluestone, 1965. Harrisonburg (Va.): Madison College.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Madison College -- History; Madison College -- Alumni and alumnae; Madison College -- Students; Madison College -- Students -- Social life and customs; James Madison University -- Students -- History; Education, Higher -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg -- History; Universities and colleges -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg -- History; Harrisonburg (Va.) -- History
Genre and Form Terms:
School records; Printed Ephemera; Concert programs; Programs (documents); Letters (correspondence); Handbooks; Invitations
- Freshman orientation, 1959, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Class absence reports, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Baptist Student Union, 1961-1962, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Event programs, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ephemera, 1961-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Annotated student handbooks, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence and invitations, 1961-1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Housing information, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Spring registration, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Virginia Lee Tadlock Brown commencement, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Class dues, room and board, 1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Program cards, 1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Data Processing 340 notebook, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Data Processing 340 loose coursework, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Math 476 test, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Rules and regulations, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)